<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hackbenchers3</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bt1">BT1</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_back">Back</string>

    <string name="BT1">
            \n
            • 4 digits in hand\n
            • Hollow bones, furcula (wish bone)\n
            • Hollow cylindrical bones\n
            • Shorter arms\n
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_bt2">BT2</string>

    <string name="BT2">
        \n
        • 3 digits in hand\n
        • Pubic boot\n
        • Tufted feathers\n
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_bt3">BT3</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="BT3">
        \n
        • Semilunate carpal in hand, feathers closed with barbules and hooks, nest brooding\n
        • Feathers closed and asymmetrical \n
        • Long arms\n
        • Toothless beak, fused wing digits, short feathered tail\n
    </string>

    <string name="triassic">
        Early mammals were very small, rarely more than a few inches in length. They were mainly herbivores or insectivores.
        Many of them were partially arboreal and nocturnal. Most, such as the shrew-like Eozostrodon, were egg layers although
        they clearly had fur and suckled their young. They had three ear bones like modern mammals and a jaw with both mammalian
        and reptilian characteristics.
    </string>

    <string name="jurrasic">
        Some of the largest animals ever to live were dinosaurs. Reptiles were also capable of laying amniotic eggs.
        Some dinosaurs, were herbivores with long necks balanced by heavy tails. Many were huge. Their skulls were relatively small,
        with nostrils carried high near their eyes.
        Adelobasileus, a shrew-like animal, had the differentiated ear and jaw bones of a mammal.
    </string>

    <string name="creataceous">
        Mammals were generally small sized. Neither true marsupials nor placentals existed until the very end,but a variety of 
        non-marsupial metatherians and non-placental eutherians had already begun to diversify. Insects diversified during the 
        Cretaceous, and ants, termites and some lepidopterans, akin to butterflies and moths, aphids, grasshoppers and wasps 
        appeared.
    </string>

    <string name="paleocene">
        There were no larger sized terrestrial animals. By this time, small insectivorous and rodent-like mammals, medium sized
        mammals were searching the forests, the first large mammals browsing on the vegetation, and carnivorous mammals stalking
        their prey evolved. Specializations, such as optimization of the teeth for a special kind of food or adaptations of the
        limbs to fast running.
    </string>

    <string name="eocene">
        Mammals became the dominant land animals during this epoch. Hoofed animals first appeared, including the famous Eohippus
        and ancestral rhinoceroses and tapirs. Early bats, rabbits, beavers, rats, mice, carnivorous mammals, and whales also
        evolved. The earliest Eocene Epoch mammals were all small, but larger species, including the elephant-sized titanothere,
        evolved towards the end.
    </string>

    <string name="oligocene">
        The appearance of the first elephants with trunks, early horses was witnessed. Early forms of canids, camels, tayassuids,
        protoceratids, and anthracotheres appeared, as did birds that possess gaping mouths for catching insects. Diurnal raptors,
        such as falcons, eagles, and hawks, along with rodents also first appeared. On land, mammals such as horses, deer, camel,
        elephants, cats, dogs, porcupines, chinchillas and primates began to dominate.
    </string>

    <string name="miocene">
        The Apes first evolved, arose. The ancestors of humans had split away from the ancestors of the chimpanzees. Mammals and
        birds were well-established. Whales and pinnipeds spread. During the late Miocene mammals were more modern, with easily
        recognizable canids, bears, procyonids, equids, beavers, deer, camelids, and whales.
    </string>

    <string name="pilocene">
        Rodents, large mastodons and opossums were widespread , while hoofed animals (camel, deer and horse) declined . Carnivores
        including the weasel family diversified, dogs and short-faced bears did well.  Cows and antelopes continued
        diversification and overtook pigs. Giraffes and platypus appeared. Bears, dogs and weasels joined cats, hyenas, civets,
        forcing hyenas to adapt as scavengers.
    </string>

    <string name="tertiary">
        Not only the dinosaurs of the terrestrial environments but also large marine reptiles, marine invertebrate faunas (rudists,
        belemnites, ammonites, bivalves), planktonic protozoans (foraminiferans), and phytoplankton were prominent. The extinction event
        at the close of the Cretaceous Period wiped out the dinosaurs, large reptiles, and many other species. This left room for new animals
        to develop .
    </string>

    <string name="RepCre">
        Turtles were also prominent in this age. Ichthyosaurs are an extinct group of dolphin-shaped marine reptiles. Their limbs were modified
        into paddles that they used for steering through water. Their tails were forked, like those of modern tunas, with bony supports in the lower
        lobe.Their bodies were long and slim; their heads were big and their teeth were sharp, similar to crocodile and alligator .
    </string>

    <string name="RepJur">
        Reptiles had strong ossified skeletons supported by advanced muscular systems for body support and locomotion. Some of the largest animals 
        ever to live were dinosaurs of the Jurassic Period.Sauropods, the “lizard hipped” dinosaurs, were herbivorous quadrupeds with long necks 
        balanced by heavy tails. Many were Carnosaurus means “meat-eating dinosaur" , large predators were also common.
    </string>

    <string name="RepTriassic">
        This group presumably gave rise to primitive dinosaurs belonging to the saurischian and ornithischian orders. The early dinosaurs were 
        bipedal, swift-moving, and relatively small. It is also called the “Age of Reptiles.” Gliding lizards are thought to have developed an 
        airfoil from skin stretched between extended ribs, which would have allowed short glides.
    </string>

    <string name="Permian">
        Permian reptile fossils are common in certain locations and include the protorosaurs, aquatic reptiles ancestral to archosaurs (dinosaurs, 
        crocodiles, and birds).Massively built and large for their day, they reached lengths of 2 to 3 metres.Synapsids (mammal-like reptiles) are 
        divided into two orders: pelycosaurs and therapsids with a remarkable change in skeletal system.
    </string>

    <string name="Carboniferous">
        The shelled eggs of reptiles were better able to withstand dry conditions, and thus did not need to be laid in water or moist ground. The 
        evolution of reptiles was spurred by the increasingly cold, dry climate of the late Carboniferous period; one of the earliest reptiles yet 
        identified, Hylonomus, appeared about 315 million years ago, and the giant (almost 10 feet long).
    </string>

    <string name="Panderichthys">
        These are lobe-finned fish. These are the only fish whose fin bones fit the tetrapod pattern of humerus, ulna and radius in the forelimb 
        and femur. This fish also had lungs and nostrils and fish has fins.
    </string>

    <string name="Elginerpeton">
        It is a very primitive tetrapod found at Scat Craig. They have  primitive limb bones found. They do not have hands or feet found,
        the animal is quite tetrapod like in the parts.
    </string>

    <string name="Hynerpeton">
        It is known only from the jaw but it is transitional between fish and amphibians. Have more advanced legs and pelvic girdle than. 
        The coronoid fangs are not present and lacked internal gills. The shape of the pectoral girdle implies both an aquatic and a terrestrial
        lifestyle.
    </string>

    <string name="Ichthyostega">
        Is the first animal with feet but the feet are different than most tetrapod feet. They are much like Acanthostega but has 7 digits on 
        his hindlimb. His legs were only good for being in water. It has four legs, lungs but still has internal gills . He has 8 digits on his 
        front leg  seven on his back feet.
    </string>

    <string name="Pederpes">
        It has 5 toes on each foot with the exception of a small relict finger/toe on the forepaw. This creature has a primitive stapes, the bone
        used in hearing.
    </string>

    <string name="PreTriassic">
        This small, primitive, egg-laying mammal fed the young with mothers milk. It  short legs, a long, pointed snout, five-toed feet
        with claws, and a long, hairy tail. It was a triconodont that belonged to the family
    </string>

    <string name="PreCretaceous">
        Its had sharp canine teeth and its cheek teeth were wide with triangular crowns. It  was an insectivore that may have also eaten
        small reptiles and perhaps scavenged. They have a  long-tailed, but a primitive pelvis and hind limbs. It may have had large eyes,
        and may have been nocturnal.
    </string>

    <string name="PreJurassic">
        It was a tiny quadruped with a long tail, a long body, and a long snout. This primitive mammal was about 4 inches (10 cm) long 
        and weighed only a few ounces.
    </string>

    <string name="Cambrian">
        It was a primitive creature with no evidence of eyes and without a well defined head. The flattened body is divided into pairs of
        segmented muscle blocks, seen as faint vertical line.
    </string>

    <string name="Ordovician">
        They lacked heavy bony shield and paired fins, but have highly exaggerated hypocercal tails. They have  bony-armored jawless.
        They have  a pairs of semicircular canals in the inner ear, as opposed to the three pairs found in the inner ears of jawed vertebrates.
        They were probably relatively good swimmers, possessing dorsal fins, paired pectoral fins, and a strong tail.
    </string>

    <string name="Silurian">
        They have  armoured jawless fish, jawed fish, spiny sharks and ray-finned fish. They do not have bony shield and paired fins, but
        have highly exaggerated hypocercal tails. It has the combination of both ray-finned and lobe-finned features, although analysis of
        the totality of its features place it closer to lobe-finned fish.
    </string>

    <string name="PreDevonian">
        The start of Devonian saw the first appearance of lobe-finned fish. They are streamlined predator about 50 centimetres long.
        They have rounded scales and body form indicate that it could have swum quickly through the water to catch prey.
        Their  bone was composed of particularly dense fibers.
    </string>

    <string name="FishCarboniferous">
        These included some, like Psammodus, with crushing pavement-like teeth adapted for grinding the shells of brachiopods, crustaceans,
        and other marine organisms. Most species of Carboniferous marine fish have been described largely from teeth, fin spines and
        dermal ossicles, with smaller freshwater fish preserved whole.
    </string>

    <string name="FishPermian">
        It had gills but no teeth,and was presumably a filter feeder. It also had only two skull bones and were covered in cubical scales.
        Each paired pectoral and pelvic fins had one spine, as did the single anal and dorsal fins, giving it a total of six spines,
        less than half that of many other spiny sharks.
    </string>

    <string name="FishJurassic">
        Feeding on smaller fish; in several cases, larger Ichthyodectidae preyed on smaller members of the family. Some species had remarkably
        large teeth while some had small ones and sucked in their prey. The largest Xiphactinus was 20 feet long.
    </string>

    <string name="FishCretaceous">
        They are the part by the long generation interval, tolerance for wide ranges of temperature and salinity, lack of predators due to
        size, and the abundance of prey items in the benthic environment. One of the genus most notable attributes are the large "fangs" at
        the front of the upper and lower jaws and on the palatine bones, leading to its misleading nickname among fossil hunters and
        paleoichthyologists, "the saber-toothed herring"
    </string>

    <string name="Cenzoic">
        Found in all oceans it was one of the largest and most powerful predators in vertebrate. They had a profound impact on marine life.
        In a typical modern flatfish, the head is asymmetric with both eyes on one side of the head.
    </string>
</resources>